<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ramblings and Wonderings</title>
    <link>https://kennyhlam.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ramblings and Wonderings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 20:27:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kennyhlam.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://kennyhlam.github.io/2016/08/getting-started</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 20:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kennyhlam.github.io/2016/08/getting-started</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So I haven&amp;rsquo;t created a website in quite a while, and well starting a blog has been on my backburner for quite a while. Anyways, I was basically inspired by a friend of mine&amp;rsquo;s blogging to get back into writing (thanks? Dennis). I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that I&amp;rsquo;ll branch back out again into things that aren&amp;rsquo;t technology-related, but this one will be. Let&amp;rsquo;s start at the beginning. I&amp;rsquo;m a back-end engineer, which basically means that anything I&amp;rsquo;ll be making may look&amp;hellip;less than glamorous, but it&amp;rsquo;ll work however it might look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start out, I wanted to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; because it&amp;rsquo;s free (but what isn&amp;rsquo;t nowadays?) and because I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of GitHub. The alternative was &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/policy/medium-terms-of-service-9db0094a1e0f#.gb3impqcl&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, and they got some flak in the past about their Terms of Service and basically being able to do a bunch of stuff without you knowing/having your explicit consent, but they&amp;rsquo;ve since &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Medium/medium-policy/commit/8d5f24a5c603a8ed9d0edaf3a7fc13a8a031a123&#34;&gt;gotten friendlier terms&lt;/a&gt;. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly worried about my blog getting re-produced, but it is nice to have the feeling that your output is your own, and Github has a great set of terms related to &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/github-terms-of-service/&#34;&gt;content ownership&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, though, Medium has a very sexy look and feel to it, but the big issue is that I would only be working on writing; I wanted to work on something where I&amp;rsquo;d be learning something else, and what better way to learn things than to customize the heck out of your own blog! GitHub Pages is also super easy to use, where everything is just a &lt;code&gt;git push -f&lt;/code&gt; away! There&amp;rsquo;s a whole bunch of other services which provide free/cheap hosting (Heroku, DigitalOcean, Amazon, etc. etc.), but there&amp;rsquo;s usually some amount of configuration and such to get it to hook into your repo, so why add in an extra middle-man when you can go directly to a repo itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good people at Github recommend using a static website generator to help with the process, and they recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Woe is me, there had to be another option! I write a bunch of Ruby code at work, and I can tell you that Ruby is awful. I mean it&amp;rsquo;s syntactic sugar, just like Python&amp;ndash;you can basically write down some English and there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance it&amp;rsquo;ll run. The issue though, is that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://benchmarksgame.alioth.debian.org/u64q/compare.php?lang=yarv&amp;amp;lang2=go&#34;&gt;slow&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s got bad support for almost-kind-of-maybe-sure-but-jokes-no &amp;ldquo;threads&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/6-static-blog-generators-arent-jekyll/&#34;&gt;options&lt;/a&gt; out there, but I won&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/11/static-website-generators-jekyll-middleman-roots-hugo-review/&#34;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; them all. In the end, I wanted something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t Ruby so I could learn something new, and I have a huge crush on golang, so Hugo was the obvious choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/quickstart/&#34;&gt;quickstart guide&lt;/a&gt; and quickly got started picking a theme, here are some of my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-identity-theme/&#34;&gt;identity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/material-design/&#34;&gt;material-design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/strata/&#34;&gt;strata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-zen/&#34;&gt;zen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose the minimalist theme for what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you sure didn&amp;rsquo;t follow the guide to a tee. In the guide, though, they do say you can have sections of your website like &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;article&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tutorial&lt;/code&gt;. However, you should be careful which template you&amp;rsquo;re using, since mine wasn&amp;rsquo;t rendering really anything cause I had run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new blog/getting-started.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out some of the templates specifically look for keys like &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt;; a variety of things are key&amp;rsquo;d off this, including the RSS feeds, so if you&amp;rsquo;re deviating from the norm, be careful to go over and find the references. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and you happen to be using a VM to do your development, you may also run into issues&amp;ndash;you really want to bind to all addresses, &lt;code&gt;0.0.0.0&lt;/code&gt;. The last little tidbit is that you basically want to copy all the &lt;code&gt;layouts&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; from the themes into your own Hugo directory (I imagine this is how they meant for people to use this). It becomes really confusing to keep track of where exactly you are in the directory when there&amp;rsquo;s a nested theme that has the same directory structure, so copying them into your top-level Hugo directory overrides the theme&amp;rsquo;s defaults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, what you really want is probably (note http for local development)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server --buildDrafts --bind 0.0.0.0 --baseUrl=http://&amp;lt;YOUR IP&amp;gt;/ 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &amp;gt; /dev/null &amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for Hugo to silently run in the background with it&amp;rsquo;s auto-update feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finally finish, careful that in your &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;, you have &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re using Github Pages. At least for Chrome, you&amp;rsquo;ll get mixed content messages (meaning some assets are &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt; and some are &lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt;), but since your Github Pages url is &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll be missing resources and your website will look like it hasn&amp;rsquo;t loaded its css (since it hasn&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo seems like a rather opinionated framework for static website generation, which isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a bad thing. However, it&amp;rsquo;s relatively young, and that&amp;rsquo;s always a bit risky. I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished reading the docs (much more of a do-er than a read-er), and some things do feel a bit clunky (you can only &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; in the top level where your &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; is, when you publish &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/usage/&#34;&gt;old assets aren&amp;rsquo;t removed&lt;/a&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;s a lack of helpful feedback such as when I made &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;posts&lt;/code&gt;, etc.) A lot of things feel like they&amp;rsquo;ve been developed so far, but not enough to the point where the defaults suit the typical use-case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, though, it was relatively easy to set up and get started with Hugo, and it provides a rather intuitive way to build a static website. While some things can be finessed, such as how to deal with your &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; directory and nested git submodules, it looks clean at the end with just some initial startup time, but writing itself was rather streamlined. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried the other options for website generation, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited at the prospect of Hugo and where it can go in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>